以前很难将 3 添加到今天，但今天却看到了……一直以来都是如此，但今天更是如此。
It had been difficult to add 3 and today it was seen... It was always seen, but today much more so.
Se había costado sumar de 3 y hoy se vio... Siempre se vio, pero hoy mucho más.
这在卡塔尔的某个时候也很引人注目，当时这支球队......
That was also noticeable at some point in Qatar when this team that is...
Eso que en algún momento también se notó en Qatar cuando le tocó perder a este equipo que es...
得到一个加分，想要再加三个，总是有那种想要赢得一切的渴望。
get a plus, want to add three again, all the time have that hunger of wanting to win everything.
sacar un plus, querer volver a sumar de tres, todo el tiempo tener ese hambre de querer ganar todo.
有必要再次添加A3，不是因为表格本身，而是因为我们所说的内容。
It was necessary to add A3 again, not because of the table itself, but because of what we are saying.
era necesario volver a sumar de A3, no por la tabla en sí, sino por esto mismo que decimos.
好吧，晚安。
Well, good night.
Bueno, buenas noches.
我不知道是否有必要添加三个，因为正如我们常说的，足球......
I don't know if it was necessary to add three because, as we always say, football...
No sé si era necesario sumar de tres porque, como siempre decimos, el fútbol...
你可以赢，也可以输。
You can win or you can lose.
Se puede ganar o se puede perder.
重要的是团队的精神。
What is important is the spirit that the team had.
Lo que es importante es el espíritu que tuvo el equipo.
在与委内瑞拉的比赛中，这种精神并没有消失，而是发挥了应有的水平。
In the match with Venezuela, that spirit was not lost, it was played as it should be played.
en el partido con Venezuela no lo perdió ese espíritu se jugó como se tiene que jugar
在上一场与哥伦比亚的比赛中，嗯，是的，但条件并不......
and in the previous one with Colombia, well, yes, but the conditions were not...
y en la anterior con Colombia, bueno, sí, pero las condiciones tampoco eran...
这是有条件的，以便这支球队在比赛结束时不会停止压迫和奔跑。
It is conditioned so that this team does not stop pressing, running at that time that had been played.
Es condicionado para que este equipo no pare de presionar, de correr a esa hora que se había jugado.
不不
no no
嗯，这是不可能的，但并不是我们不想这样做。
Well, it wasn't possible but it wasn't that we didn't want to.
Bueno, no se pudo pero no era que no queríamos.
太好了，我们赢了。
So well, we won.
Entonces bueno, ganamos.
与我们的身份，但我想他想说的是，它从未失去过，是我的感觉...
with our identity, but I think what he wanted to say is that it was never lost, it is the feeling that I...
con nuestra identidad, pero creo que lo que quería decir es que no se perdió nunca, es la sensación que a mí me...
它给了我这种精神，球队仍然拥有这种精神。
It gives me that spirit, the team still has it.
me da ese espíritu, el equipo lo sigue teniendo.
重要的是我们踢了一场精彩的比赛，球迷们也很高兴离开。
The important thing is that we played a good game and that the fans left happy.
Lo importante es que hicimos un buen partido y que el hincha se fue contento.
莱昂内尔，晚安。
Leonel, good night.
Leonel, buenas noches.
这里是红色电台的古斯塔沃·亚罗赫 (Gustavo Yarroch)。
Here Gustavo Yarroch for Radio La Red.
Acá Gustavo Yarroch para Radio La Red.
我们刚刚和同事谈论梅西的表现。
We were just talking with colleagues about Messi's performance.
Recién hablábamos con los colegas respecto de la actuación que tuvo Messi.
我们回顾了他身披国家队球衣的精彩表现
and we reviewed the brilliant performances he had with the national team shirt
y repasábamos las actuaciones brillantes que tuvo con la camiseta de la selección
我想问你，你是否还记得他中比今天更完整的人。
I want to ask you if you remember any of him that are more complete than today's.
Te quiero preguntar si recordás alguna de él más completa que la de hoy.
当然，他打过比这一场更好的比赛，这是肯定的。
Surely he has had better games than this one, for sure.
Seguramente sí haya tenido mejores partidos que este, seguro.
我想到了这一点，但事实并非如此……
That comes to mind, but it's not...
Eso me viene a la cabeza, pero es que no...
永远不会停止惊喜和...
never ceases to surprise and...
no deja de sorprender y...
最重要的是，我认为很快我就坐下来和巴勃罗交谈，我告诉他这就是
and above all I think that well in a moment I sit down and talk to Pablo and I tell him well this is
y sobre todo creo que ya bueno en un momento yo me siento y hablo con Pablo y le digo bueno esto es
能够坐在这张长凳上看到他们所做的事情真是太棒了。
It's wonderful to enjoy this, to be able to sit on this bench and see the things they do.
Es maravilloso disfrutar esto, poder estar sentado en este banco de suplentes y ver las cosas que hacen.
并且让他的团队陪他，因为最终还是要团队陪他。
and let his team accompany him, because in the end the team has to accompany him.
y que su equipo acompañe, porque al final el equipo tiene que acompañarlo.
这是一件美妙的事情，永远让我们感到惊讶。
It is something wonderful and never stops surprising us.
Es algo maravilloso y no para de sorprendernos.
尽可能长时间地玩，这是我对你的唯一要求，因为这是......
Play as long as you can, that's the only thing I ask of you, because it's a...
que juegue hasta que pueda, es lo único que le pido, porque es una...
很高兴在足球场上看到并参与其中。
A pleasure to see and have on a soccer field.
Un placer verlo y tenerlo dentro de una cancha de fútbol.
嗯，是的，在这里。
Well, yes, here.
Bien, sí, acá.
来自《Cadena 3》的马塞洛·兰贝蒂。
Marcelo Lamberti from Cadena 3.
Marcelo Lamberti de Cadena 3.
在胜利和出色的表现之后，你一定已经多次进入更衣室了。
You must have entered the locker room many times after victories and good performances.
Te habrá tocado entrar y te ha tocado entrar muchas veces al vestuario después de victorias y de buenas actuaciones.
从那里他们感觉这是最大的之一。
From there they have the feeling that this was one of the maximum.
Por ahí tienen la sensación que esta fue de las máximas.
你对男孩们说什么了？
What did you say to the boys?
¿Qué le dijiste a los muchachos?
你已经跟他说过话、表达过什么了吗？
Have you already spoken, expressed something to him?
¿Ya hablaste, le expresaste algo?
我还没说话，比赛结束后没有人，我走进办公室，嗯，进入……
I didn't speak yet, there was no one after the game, I went into my office, well, into...
No hablé todavía, no había ninguno después del partido, me metí en mi oficina, bueno, en la oficina de...
呃？
¿eh?
好吧，我想他们现在要离开了，我不会见到他们，但是好吧，他们已经知道我们必须继续沿着这条线以及我在
and well, I think they're leaving now, I'm not going to see them but well, they already know that we have to continue along this line and what I told them in the
y bueno yo creo que ya se van no los voy a ver pero pero bueno ellos ya saben que hay que seguir en esta línea y lo que le dije en el
中场休息意味着我们必须继续比赛。
The break at halftime meant we had to continue.
El descanso en el entretiempo era que había que seguir.
首先是因为我们的球迷想看到球队，其次是因为......
First because our fans are wanting to see the team, second because...
Primero porque está nuestra hinchada queriendo ver al equipo, segundo porque...
尊重你的对手意味着继续以同样的方式打球。
Respecting your opponent means continuing to play the same way.
Respetar al rival significa seguir jugando de la misma manera.
第三，因为我们也想给其他孩子一个机会，而那些必须进入的孩子必须尝试......
And third, because we also wanted to give other kids a chance and those kids who had to enter had to try...
Y tercero, porque queríamos darle oportunidad también a otros chicos y esos chicos que tenían que entrar tenían que intentar...
以他的队友们的方式打球，要做到这一点，他必须继续
play the same way his teammates had played and for that to happen he had to continue with
jugar de la misma manera que habían jugado sus compañeros y para que eso suceda tenía que seguir con
以同样的渴望和同样的强度。
with the same desire and the same intensity.
con la misma gana y la misma intensidad.
莱昂内尔，这里是奥克塔维奥·帕特里克，是维克多·雨果的报告员。
Leonel, here Octavio Patric, for rapporteurs with Víctor Hugo.
Leonel, acá Octavio Patric, para relatores con Víctor Hugo.
我请你写一段关于奇科·帕斯的文章，我们看到他非常自信。
I ask you for a paragraph about Chico Paz, we saw him with great self-confidence.
Te pido un párrafo sobre el Chico Paz, lo vimos con mucho desparpajo.
感动了，他踩了它，但是嘿，我更喜欢你评论它。
Moved, he stepped on it, but hey, I prefer that you comment on it.
Movedizo, la pisaba, pero bueno, prefiero que lo comentes vos.
你有没有预料到他会如此清醒？
Did you expect this from him, that he seemed so lucid?
¿Esperabas esto de él, que se lo viera tan lúcido?
谢谢。
Gracias.
我首先想说的是...
The first thing I want to say is...
Lo primero que quiero decir es...
一个男孩真是太好了
It's very nice that a boy who
es muy lindo que un chico que
他的父亲有...
that his dad has...
que tenga su papá...
我在纽维尔和父亲一起踢球，我在这里认识他。
I played with Father at Newell's, I know him here.
Yo jugué con el Padre en Newell's, lo conozco aquí.
巴勃罗·帕斯 (Pablo Paz) 将为他儿子的首次亮相感到高兴。
to Pablo Paz and will be happy for his son's debut.
a Pablo Paz y estará contento por el debut de su hijo.
而他的儿子来并不是因为他是他的儿子，而是因为他踢得很好。
And his son comes not because he is his son, but because he plays very well.
Y su hijo no viene porque es su hijo, sino porque juega muy bien.
又因为在这里它可以一点一点地给我们带来很多东西。
and because here it can bring us many things little by little.
y porque acá puede aportarnos muchas cosas poco a poco.
今天我们给了他一些我认为......
Today we gave him those minutes that I think...
Hoy le dimos esos minutos que creo que...
他需要这几分钟的时间来让自己对这件球衣产生认同感。
He needed these minutes for him to feel identified with this shirt.
que para que él se siente identificado con esta camiseta lo necesitaba estos minutos.
他踢得很好，他踢得很好，他踢得很好。
And he plays well, he plays football very well, he plays the ball very well.
Y juega bien, juega muy bien al fútbol, juega muy bien a la pelota.
他善于交际，除此之外他还有力量，他有目标。
and he associates well and on top of that he has strength, he has a goal.
y se asocia bien y encima tiene fuerza, tiene gol.
好吧，我不能贡献，它很高，是的，它是......
Well, I can't contribute, it's high, yes, it's...
Bueno, no puedo aportar, es alto, sí, es...
他是一名优秀的球员，最重要的是，他也是一个很棒的孩子。
He is a good player and above all a great boy too.
Es un buen jugador y sobre todo un gran chico también.
他有一个伟大的头脑，他将为我们做出贡献，但一点一点地。
He has a great head and he is going to contribute to us, but little by little.
que tiene una gran cabeza y a nosotros nos va a aportar, pero poco a poco.
今天他有他的会议记录，我们将把它们视为......
Today he had his minutes and we will take them as...
Hoy tuvo sus minutos y los llevaremos como...
尽我们所能，随着时间的需要，如果他值得上场，他就会上场。
as we can and as time requires and if he deserves to play, he will play.
como podamos y como el tiempo requiera y si merece jugar, jugará.
约阿内尔，我是米特广播电台的保罗·菲利皮尼。
Yoanel, this is Paulo Filippini from Radio Miter.
Yoanel, aquí Paulo Filippini de Radio Mitre.
今天你决定放...
Today you made the decision to put...
Hoy tomaste la decisión de poner...
里奥、劳塔罗和朱利安表现得非常好。
Leo, Lautaro and Julián did really well.
a Leo, a Lautaro y a Julián, lo hicieron realmente muy bien.
我想问你，对手是玻利维亚这个事实与做出这个决定有多大关系。
and I wanted to ask you how much the fact that the rival was Bolivia had to do with making that decision.
y quería consultarte cuánto tuvo que ver que el rival fuera Bolivia para tomar esa decisión.
如果您认为这也可以与排名更高的竞争对手重复。
and if you think this can be repeated with higher-ranking rivals as well.
y si crees que esto se puede repetir con rivales de mayor jerarquía también.
不，那会损害玻利维亚的声誉。
No, that would be discrediting Bolivia.
No, eso sería desmerecer a Bolivia.
无论这个决定是什么，很明显这个决定
Whatever that decision was, it is evident that the decision
que haya sido esa decisión, sí es evidente que la decisión
这是因为在整个电话会议中，我们失去了能够参加比赛的球员
It has been because throughout the call we have lost players who can play in a
ha sido porque a lo largo de la convocatoria hemos perdido jugadores que pueden jugar en un
在一个乐队中，他的名字叫尼科·冈萨雷斯 (Nico González)，他总是为我们提供帮助。
in a band, his name is Nico González, who has always given us a hand.
en una banda, llámese Nico González, que siempre nos ha dado una mano.
更不用说安赫尔·迪玛丽亚了，他不再来了，我们一直有他......
Not to mention Ángel Di María, who doesn't come anymore, we always had him...
por no citarlo a Ángel Di María, que ya no viene más, que lo teníamos siempre...
无论是他上场还是尼科上场，他总是给我们这种可能性。
whether he played or Nico played and he always gave us that possibility.
si jugaba él o jugaba Nico y siempre nos daba esa posibilidad.
当玩家跌倒时，他们必须寻找最好的选择。
When players fall, they have to look for the best option.
cuando se van cayendo los jugadores tiene que buscar la mejor opción.
在委内瑞拉，我们选择了蒂亚戈，我认为如果球场状况良好的话，蒂亚戈很适合他。
In Venezuela we had opted for Thiago, who I think was a match for him if the pitch had been in good condition.
En Venezuela habíamos optado por Thiago, que creo que era un partido para él si la cancha hubiera estado en condiciones.
而这场比赛我们就是为了这个
and this game we are for this
y este partido estamos por por esta
我们相信可以为我们提供解决方案，特别是因为他们的比赛方式。
solution that we believe could be given to us, especially because of how they played.
solución que creemos que nos podía dar, sobre todo por cómo jugaban ellos.
我们相信，在中锋和边路之间的朱利安可以......
We believe that Julián there, between center and wing, could...
creemos que Julián ahí, entre centro y lateral, podía...
造成伤害，最重要的是他有工作。
do harm and above all that he has work.
hacer daño y sobre todo que tiene trabajo.
今天的朱利安
Julian today
Julián hoy
除了进球之外，他还像往常一样做着自己的工作，但他的位置肯定要多一些。
In addition to scoring the goal, he does the job as he always does but a little more in a position that surely
además de hacer el gol el trabajo como siempre lo hace pero un poco más en una posición que seguramente
的框架内
within the framework of
en el marco de
也许不是你喜欢的人，但为了团队，所有这些人都做了一切。
It may not be the one you like, but for the team all these guys do everything.
no sea la que le guste, pero por el equipo todos estos chicos hacen de todo.
最后，结果很好。
And, in the end, it turned out well.
Y, al final, salió bien.
但是，我再说一遍，它可以重复，是的。
But, I repeat, it can be repeated, yes.
Pero, repito, se puede volver a repetir, sí.
但我们也可以按照我们一直以来的方式进行比赛，这一点我们已经很清楚了。
but we can also play the way we have been playing, that is already clear to us.
pero también podemos jugar de la manera que veníamos jugando, eso ya lo tenemos claro.
教练，莱昂内尔，你好吗？
Coach, Leonel, how are you doing?
Entrenador, Leonel, ¿cómo te va?
哈维尔·阿帕里西奥 (Javier Aparicio)，萨尔塔队 10 号。
Javier Aparicio, for the Salta team 10.
Javier Aparicio, para el equipo 10 de Salta.
今天是第 81 场比赛。
Today was game number 81.
Hoy fue el partido número 81.
有一天，我感觉他们必须穿上工作服，跳进泥里，他们做到了。
The other day I get the feeling that they had to put on their overalls, jump into the mud, they did it.
El otro día me da la sensación que se tuvieron que poner el mameluzco, saltar al barro, lo hicieron.
今天他们穿上了燕尾服，他们留下了这个。
Today they put on the tailcoat, they left this.
Hoy se pusieron el frac, dejaron esto.
在你为球队提供的足球结构中，你会如何定义自己？
How would you define yourself in the football structure that you give to your team?
¿Cómo te definirías vos en la estructura futbolística que le das a tu equipo?
现在有81场比赛了，一定有办法，有步骤的方法。
Now with 81 games there must be a way, a step-by-step method.
Ya con 81 partidos debe haber un modo, un método escalón.
你有这个定义吗？
Do you have that defined?
¿Lo tenés definido a eso?
是的，安切洛蒂说的那个，谁说的是对的，说了类似的话，不要碰它，尽量少干预。
Yes, the one that Ancelotti said, who said what is right, said something like that, don't touch it, intervene as little as possible.
Sí, el que dijo Ancelotti, que dijo lo que anda bien, algo así dijo, no tocarlo, intervenir lo menos posible.
就是这个方法。
That's the method.
Ese es el método.
我想这就是美德。
I imagine that is the virtue.
Me imagino que esa es la virtud.
我们已经做好了准备，从逻辑上讲我们也做好了准备，但最终他们还是上场了。
that we have and logically we prepare, but in the end they play.
que tenemos nosotros y lógicamente nosotros preparamos, pero al final juegan ellos.
毫无疑问，还有其他教练，而且是......
There is no doubt, there are other coaches and it is...
No hay duda, hay otros entrenadores y es...
每个人都可以自由发表意见，他们说他们的球队打得很好是因为
Everyone is free to give their opinion, they say that their team plays well because
es libre cada uno de opinar que dicen que bueno su equipo juegan bien porque
因为有人告诉他要把事情做好或者做任何事。
because one tells him to get it right or anything.
porque uno le manda acertar o cualquier cosa.
就我而言...
In my case...
En mi caso...
在这种情况下这可能是正确的，但在我的情况下，很明显他们才是玩游戏的人。
which in that case may be true, but in my case it is evident that they are the ones who play.
que en ese caso puede ser verdad, pero en mi caso es evidente que los que juegan son ellos.
我们所做的就是为他们提供我们认为可以帮助他们的工具。
And what we do is give them that tool that we believe can help them.
Y nosotros lo que hacemos es darle esa herramienta que creemos que les puede ayudar.
今天的表现，跟教练、今天球员的表现有什么关系呢？
Today's performance, what does the coach, the performance of today's players have to do with it?
La actuación de hoy, ¿qué tiene que ver el entrenador, la actuación de los jugadores de hoy?
这是不可能的，如果你看到进球，看到他们的表现，我不会像他们那样在两条线之间传球。
It's impossible, if you see the goals, you see the plays they made, I don't pass the ball between the lines like they pass it.
Es imposible, si ves los goles, ves las jugadas que hicieron, yo no paso la pelota entre líneas como la pasan ellos.
我们给他们工具并告诉他们我们如何攻击。
We give them the tool and tell them how we can attack.
Nosotros le damos la herramienta y le decimos cómo podemos atacar.
我们必须防守，我认为所有教练都会这样做。
We have to defend, which I think all coaches do.
Tenemos que defender, que creo que eso lo hacen todos los entrenadores.
但最大的区别在于材料。
But the big difference is the material there is.
Pero la gran diferencia es la materia que hay.
原材料是令人难以置信的。
The raw material is something incredible.
La materia prima es algo increíble.
正如我们常说的，你必须把车停在高速公路上，然后让它走，尽量不要撞车。
And you have to, as we always say, put the car on top of the highway and let it go and try not to crash.
Y hay que poner, como siempre decimos, el auto arriba de la autopista y que vaya e intentar que no choque.
就是这样...
That's what...
Eso es lo que...
我们认为这很重要，并且从一开始我们就理解了它。
We think it is important and we understood it from the first moment.
Creemos que es importante y lo entendimos en el primer momento.
然后，从逻辑上讲，就会出现必须做出决定的困难时刻。
And then, logically, there are difficult moments where decisions have to be made.
y después lógicamente hay momentos difíciles donde hay que tomar decisiones.
这就是那里，也许...
And that's where, maybe...
Y ahí es donde, a lo mejor...
所做的一切都有一点好处。
The good thing lies a little in everything that has been done.
radica un poco lo bueno de todo lo que se ha hecho.
但在足球层面上，我认为干预是必要的。
But at a football level I think that intervening is necessary.
pero a nivel futbolístico creo que intervenir lo necesario.
埃塞奎尔·苏亚雷斯 (Ezequiel Suárez) 代表多洛雷斯·莱里奥 (Dolores Llerio) 做出承诺。
Here, Ezequiel Suárez, for Dolores Llerio Commitment.
Acá, Ezequiel Suárez, para Dolores Llerio Compromiso.
说到它有什么关系，还有Conexa，它有什么关系
Speaking of what it has to do with, and also for Conexa, what it has to do with
Hablando de que lo que tiene que ver con, y también para Conexa, lo que tiene que ver con
教练，今晚所有球员都这样做了，但肯定是为了
the coach that all the players did this tonight but surely for the
el técnico que esto hicieron todos los jugadores esta noche pero seguramente para los
你的80场比赛，肯定是......
80 games of yours, it will surely have been...
80 partidos tuyos, seguramente habrá sido...
也是他们送的礼物，我说很高兴，即使你不说，
a gift from them too, and I say and happy, even if you don't say it,
un regalo de ellos también, y digo y feliz, más allá que vos no lo digas,
因为你所想到的一切都是在赛场上实现的，你也一定会为此感到高兴。
because everything you think about is achieved on the field of play, you will surely be happy about that too.
porque todo lo que se piensa se logra en el terreno del juego, seguramente estará feliz por eso también.
是的，或多或少相似的答案。
Yes, more or less similar answer.
Sí, más o menos parecida respuesta.
我不认为他们有这个想法...
I don't think they have the idea...
Yo creo que ellos no tienen la idea...
他们的教练、球员最后的比赛量。
the amount of game that their coaches, the players, have at the end.
la cantidad de partido que tienen sus entrenadores, los jugadores, al final.
重要的是球员们要上场比赛。
The important thing is that the players go out on the field and play.
Lo importante es que los jugadores salgan a la cancha y jueguen.
为他们的球队为他们的员工一如既往，从逻辑上讲，如果他们像这样踢球，他们就是在为教练踢球，而教练也同样为他们踢球。
for their team for their people as they always do and logically if they play like this they play for the coach who also
por su equipo por su gente como lo hacen siempre y lógicamente si juegan así juegan por el entrenador que también
就像他们一样。
is just like them.
está igual que ellos.
我不知道他们是否知道我们正在玩的游戏，但确实如此
I don't know if they are aware of the games we are playing, but it is true that
No sé si estarán al tanto de los partidos que llevamos, pero sí es verdad que
重要的是，他们付出了自己，就像他们今天付出了自己一样。
What it is about is that they give themselves as they have given themselves today.
Lo que se trata es que ellos se brinden como se han brindado hoy.
好吧，你甚至可以失去它，但这样味道就会不同。
And well, you can even lose it, but this way the flavor is different.
Y bueno, se puede incluso perder, pero de esta manera el sabor es diferente.
莱昂内尔、维托·阿马尔菲塔诺代表马德普拉塔。
Lionel, Vito Amalfitano for Mar del Plata.
Lionel, Vito Amalfitano para Mar del Plata.
确实，他们在比赛，但你把球队组合在一起。
It is true that they play, but you put together the team.
Es cierto que juegan ellos, pero el equipo lo armaste vos.
让我们暂时忘记你是世界冠军、美国双料冠军。
Let's forget that you are world champion, double champion of America, for a moment.
olvidémonos que sos campeón del mundo, doble campeón de América, por un momento.
让我们想想莱昂内尔·斯卡洛尼 (Lionel Scaloni)，他是一名足球运动员，后来成为一名教练。
and let's think about Lionel Scaloni, a footballer who became a coach.
y pensemos en Lionel Scaloni, futbolista que se transformó en entrenador.
管理团队的转变意味着什么？
What does it mean in that transition to manage a team...
¿Qué significa en esa transición llegar a dirigir un equipo...
演奏得如此完美，速度如此精确。
that plays so perfectly, with such precision in speed.
que juega tan a la perfección, con tanta precisión en velocidad.
这是足球历史上很少有教练能够拥有的特权。
a privilege that few coaches in the history of football could have had.
un privilegio que por ahí pocos entrenadores en la historia del fútbol pudieron tener.
这对你来说意味着什么？
What does that mean to you?
¿Qué significa para vos eso?
这就是为什么答案与上一个类似，它是......
That's why the answer is similar to the previous one, it's something...
Por eso la respuesta es similar a la anterior, es algo...
让我们看看，你如何享受它？
Let's see, how do you enjoy it?
A ver, ¿cómo disfrutan ustedes?
教练喜欢在外面吗？
Does the coach enjoy outside?
¿Disfruta el entrenador afuera?
我们也看到同样的情况。
We see the same.
Vemos lo mismo.
我们看到球的速度、它是什么样的、控制，最重要的是，之后......
We see the speed of the ball, what it is like, the control and, above all, after...
Vemos la velocidad de pelota, cómo es, el control y, sobre todo, después...
夺回球权的意图...
The intention to recover the ball...
La intención de recuperar la pelota...
尽快。
as quickly as possible.
lo más rápido posible.
这是非常令人高兴的事情，并且为他们理解了这一信息而感到自豪。
That's something very nice to see and proud that they understand the message.
Eso es algo muy lindo de ver y orgulloso de que ellos entiendan el mensaje.
但是，我再说一遍，这件事......
But, I repeat, the matter...
Pero, repito, la materia...
prima 使一切变得更加容易，并且每个解释都可以很快被理解。
prima makes everything much easier and each explanation is understood quickly.
prima hace de que todo sea mucho más fácil y cada explicación la entiendan rápidamente.
莱昂内尔，在你左边。
Lionel, here to your left.
Lionel, acá a tu izquierda.
尼科·贝拉多 (Niko Berardo) 为 Le 报社拍摄。
Niko Berardo for the newspaper Le.
Niko Berardo para el diario Le.
他谈到了很多关于这场6比0剩下的事情。
He spoke a lot about what was left of this 6 to 0.
Hablaba mucho de lo que quedó de este 6 a 0.
但这次双人约会也有很多调味料，我的意思是，有 5 名球员被删除或从名单中删除。
but this double date also had a lot of seasoning, I mean, 5 players were dropped or dropped from the list.
pero también esta doble fecha tuvo bastante condimento, digo, se te bajaron o se te cayeron 5 jugadores de la lista.
比赛中迪乌受到了处罚，库蒂也受到了处罚。
There was the sanction to Diu, also that of Cuti in the game.
Estaba la sanción a Diu, también la de Cuti en el partido.
在委内瑞拉发生了什么，行程我不知道需要多少个小时。
what happened in Venezuela, the trip of I don't know how many hours.
lo que pasó en Venezuela, el viaje de no sé cuántas horas.
平衡或教学还剩下什么？
What was left of balance or teaching as well?
¿Qué les quedó de saldo o de enseñanza también?
我想所有这一切也将超越这个 6 比 0，这才是最终让作品熠熠生辉的原因。
All of this that I imagine will also have marked beyond this 6 to 0, which is what ends up giving shine to the work.
Todo eso que imagino que también habrá marcado más allá de este 6 a 0 que es lo que termina dándole brillo al laburo.
是的，好问题，因为...
Yes, good question because...
Sí, buena pregunta porque...
对我们来说，似乎我们专注了一个月，这是非常值得的。
For us it seems that we were focused for a month, it was a very
para nosotros parece que estuvimos concentrados un mes, fue una fecha muy
很重，装了很多东西，第一个把它们拿下来，第二个
very heavy, very loaded a lot of things, the first one takes them down, the second one
muy pesada, muy cargada un montón de cosas, la primera las baja, la segunda la
可能不知道在哪里训练，是否可以进入委内瑞拉，如果不能进入。
possibility of not knowing where to train, if we could enter Venezuela, if we could not enter.
posibilidad de no saber dónde entrenar, si podíamos entrar a Venezuela, si no podíamos entrar.
然后飓风发生在我们身上，然后比赛前一天到达......
Then the hurricane happened to us, then the arrival the day before the game was...
Después nos pasó lo del huracán, después la llegada el día anterior al partido fue...
可怕的是，再配上水，很多东西。
Terrible, then the match with water, many things.
terrible, después el partido con agua, muchísimas cosas.
我们最终成功克服了这个问题，当一个人
that we managed to overcome in the end, when one
que logramos superar al final, cuando uno
我们总是告诉他，当一个人有做某事的倾向时
What we always tell him is that, when one has a predisposition to do things
Lo que siempre le decimos es eso, cuando uno tiene predisposición por hacer las cosas
而且他精神很好，遇事不恼，不生气。
and he is in good spirits, things happen and one does not get annoyed, one does not get angry.
y tiene buen ánimo, las cosas pasan y uno no se fastidia, no se enoja.
因为上周确实很沉重。
because really the previous week was heavy.
porque realmente la semana anterior fue pesada.
以及球员们对这一切的倾向
and the predisposition that the players have had to all that
y la predisposición que han tenido ellos los jugadores a todo ese
混乱，如果你可以称之为混乱的话，已经达到了最大程度。
Chaos, if you can call it, has been maximum.
caos, si se puede llamar, ha sido máxima.
这是最大的，因为我们已经
It has been maximum because we have been
Ha sido máxima porque hemos estado
在机场待了好几个小时，在旅途中也花了好几个小时。
Many hours in airports, many hours traveling.
Muchísimas horas en los aeropuertos, muchísimas horas de viaje.
被锁在酒店里，不知道我们是否可以训练以及所有这些东西
locked in hotels without knowing if we could train and all that stuff and it
encerrados en los hoteles sin saber si podíamos entrenar y todas esas cosas y ello
他们对这一点的理解非常好，所以让我印象深刻的是他们......
They've understood it incredibly well, so what it leaves me with is that they're...
lo han entendido increíblemente bien, entonces lo que me deja es que ellos están...
非常投入事业，为国家队效力。
very involved in the cause, in playing for the national team.
muy metido en la causa, en jugar para la selección.
因为这样他们就能很好地训练并以同样的方式比赛。
because then they go and train very well and play in the same way.
porque después van y entrenan muy bien y juegan de la misma manera.
嗯，这是一个非常积极的信号。
Well, that's a very positive sign.
Bueno, eso es una señal muy positiva.
莱昂内尔，内斯托尔·克利瓦蒂，来自拉斐拉的旁观者。
Leonel here, Néstor Clivaty, from Rafaela's spectator.
Leonel aquí, Néstor Clivaty, del espectador de Rafaela.
嗯，这样的速度让我们记者失业了。
Well, this pace is leaving us journalists out of work.
Bueno, este ritmo nos están dejando sin trabajo los periodistas.
以这样的速度，没什么可问的，对吧？
There's little to ask at such a pace, right?
Hay poco para preguntar tal el ritmo, ¿no?
以及团队的辉煌。
and the brilliance of the team.
y el brillo del equipo.
尼科·帕斯 (Nico Paz) 首次亮相后，已有近 50 名玩家。
With the debut of Nico Paz there are almost 50 players.
Con el debut de Nico Paz son casi 50 los jugadores.
他们在你的周期中首次亮相，这是你的想法的一部分
that in your cycle they debuted, it is part of what you think
que en tu ciclo debutaron, es parte creés
关于这个叫做身份的东西，它可以被预测到未来......
about this thing called identity and that can be projected into the future as...
de esto de que se llama identidad y que se puede proyectar a futuro como...
作为座右铭，也就是说，有谎言
as a motto, that is, there lies
como lema, es decir, allí radica
你所提供的一点点。
a little bit of what you offer.
un poco esto que ustedes ofrecen.
永久作为教练组决策的资产。
permanently as an asset of the decisions of your coaching staff.
permanentemente como un activo de las decisiones de tu cuerpo técnico.
谢谢。
Gracias.
阿根廷队依靠的是最好的球员。
The Argentine team relies on having the best.
La selección argentina radica en que estén los mejores.
并且始终不放松。
and that there is continually a non-relaxation.
y que continuamente haya un no relajamiento.
我们相信，这种缺乏放松的情况很大程度上来自于那些非常渴望在那里的年轻男孩。
And we believe that this lack of relaxation comes a lot from young boys who have a tremendous desire to be there.
Y creemos que ese no relajamiento viene mucho de los chicos jóvenes que tienen unas ganas bárbaras de estar.
在不排除任何人的情况下，找到一个同龄球员是非常困难的
Without ruling out anyone, it is very difficult to find a player of an age
sin descartar a nadie es muy difícil encontrar un jugador de una edad
先进了，我不想说坏话。
advanced, I don't want to speak badly.
avanzada, no quiero hablar mal.
这可能会损害其他人的立场，然后我们就会抛弃这些抱有野蛮幻想的人。
that could compromise someone else's position and then we throw away these guys who have a barbaric illusion.
que pueda comprometer el puesto de otro y entonces tiramos a estos chicos que tienen una ilusión bárbara.
也许是缺乏经验，是的，但是......
maybe the lack of experience, well yes, but...
que a lo mejor la falta de experiencia, bueno sí, pero...
但他们对踢足球了解很多，这些孩子促使现在在那里的人不要放弃。
But they know a lot about playing football and those kids push those who are there now not to want to give up.
pero jugar al fútbol saben muchísimo y esos chicos empujan a que los que están ahora no quieran bajarse.
他们不想因为吃到黄牌而输掉下一场比赛。
They don't want to get a yellow card to lose the next game.
no quieran que le saquen una amarilla para perder el siguiente partido.
他们想要在那里，他们想要在那里，这是一个非常好的迹象。
They want to be there and they want to be there, and that is a very good sign.
quieran estar y quieran estar, y eso es una señal muy buena.
因为也许他们知道，如果他们给那个队友上场的机会，他可能会丢掉工作。
because maybe they know that if they give that teammate the chance to play, he might lose his job.
porque a lo mejor saben que si les da la posibilidad a ese compañero de jugar a lo mejor puede perder el puesto.
这就是感觉，也许不是那样的，但这是我们拥有的感觉，而且是有效的。
That is the feeling, then maybe it is not like that, but it is a feeling that we have and that is valid.
Esa es la sensación, después a lo mejor no es así, pero es una sensación que nosotros tenemos y que es válida.
从逻辑上讲，那些推动的人是年轻人，那些有选择的孩子，他们见证了他们成为世界冠军。
and those who push are the young people, logically, those kids who have a choice, who have seen them become world champions.
y los que empujan son los jóvenes, lógicamente, esos chicos que tienen una elección, que han visto a ellos ser campeón del mundo.
最近，对于那些孩子来说今天来到这里是一个巨大的幻想。
recently and for those kids to be here today is a huge illusion.
hace poco y que para esos chicos estar hoy acá es una ilusión enorme.
呼吸的空气为我们带来了很多。
That breath of air generates a lot for us.
Esa bocanada de aire a nosotros nos genera un montón.
训练进行得很顺利。
The training goes very well.
Los entrenamientos salen muy bien.
这些孩子的行为堪称典范。
and those kids behave in an exemplary way.
y esos chicos se portan de una manera ejemplar.
一切都在顺利进行中。
Everything is well underway.
Está todo bien encaminado.
快点。
Come on.
Vamos.
莱昂内尔，晚安。
Leonel, good night.
Leonel, buenas noches.
祝贺胜利。
Congratulations on the victory.
Felicitaciones por la victoria.
来自美洲图库曼 (América Tucumán) 的 Daniel Urueña 以及更多体育运动。
Daniel Urueña from América Tucumán and more sports.
Daniel Urueña de América Tucumán y más deportes.
这些球员都是 escalonistas，因为他们会按照你的要求去做，胡利安·阿尔瓦雷斯 (Julian Álvarez) 的牺牲可能是......
These players are escalonistas because they do what you ask, the sacrifice of Julián Álvarez playing in a position that maybe...
Estos jugadores son escalonistas porque hacen lo que le pedís, el sacrificio de Julián Álvarez jugando en una posición que a lo mejor...
正如你所说，他不太喜欢，但他还是答应了。
As you said, he doesn't like it that much, but he complies.
como bien lo decía vos, no le agrade tanto, pero cumple.
进来的都是整个刮下来的，是没有裂纹的精选。
The one that enters is scraped whole, it is a selection that shows no cracks.
el que entra se raspa entero, es una selección que no muestra fisuras.
另一个问题与那里的图库马诺和法玛拉有关，那就是这里的宫殿。
And the other question has to do with Tucumano and Famaillá from there, that is the palace here.
Y la otra pregunta tiene que ver como Tucumano y de Famaillá de ahí, ese es aquí el palacio.
您如何看待操作后返回此选择的情况。
How did you see it post-operation in the return of this selection.
cómo lo viste post operación en el retorno de esta selección.
球员都是来自阿根廷国家队的球员，他们在比赛中。
The players are players from the Argentine national team and they play.
Los jugadores son jugadores de la selección argentina y juegan.
对于阿根廷队来说，谁坐在替补席上。
for the Argentine team, whoever is sitting on the substitute bench.
por la selección argentina, este quien esté sentado en el banco de suplentes.
我现在在这里，我重复一遍，当有其他教练的时候我说过很多次，我曾是国家队的球员。
I am here now and I repeat and I said it a lot of times when there were other coaches that I have been a player in the national team.
Estoy yo ahora y repito y lo dije un montón de veces cuando había otros entrenadores que yo he sido jugador a la selección.
他为球队深深地敬了一杯酒，无论谁坐在替补席上，这都不会发生。
He gave you a deep toast to the team and it didn't matter who was sitting on the bench and that will always happen that way.
te brindaba a fondo por la selección y daba igual quién estaba sentado en el banco y eso pasará siempre así.
今天是我，明天是你们的教练，球员也会像今天一样来奉献自己。
Today it's me and tomorrow it will be your coach and the player will come and offer himself as they did today.
Hoy soy yo y el día de mañana será tu técnico y el jugador vendrá y se va a brindar como se brindaron estos hoy.
当你获胜时，一切都会被放大。
When you win everything is magnified.
Cuando ganas se magnifica todo.
我总是说同样的话。
I always say the same thing.
Siempre digo lo mismo.
关于帕拉的事情，嗯，我们对帕拉来说，很明显......
And the thing about Pala, well, we to Pala it is evident that...
Y lo de Pala, bueno, nosotros a Pala es evidente que lo...
这些分钟可能不是他想要的。
The minutes may not be what he would like to have.
Los minutos a lo mejor no son los que él quisiera tener.
但当一个团队如此努力时，我们就知道它就在那里。
But when a team works so much, we know it is there.
Pero cuando un equipo funciona tanto, pero nosotros sabemos que está.
他总是在那儿，对我们来说非常重要，他是一个男孩，当他被召唤去参加这项事业时，他就在那儿。
who is always there and for us is very important, he is a boy who when called to the cause is there and when
que siempre está y para nosotros es importantísimo es un chico que cuando lo llama a la causa está y cuando
他必须训练，他是第一个训练好的，我们有很多人，我们称他为士兵，有很多
He has to train, he is the first to train well and there are a lot of us, we call him a soldier, there are a lot of
tiene que entrenar es el primero que entrena bien y hay un montón nosotros llamamos soldado hay un montón de
像帕拉这样的士兵和前几天被征召参加这项事业的德国人来说，是一个巨大的匹配。
of soldiers like Pala, Germán, who the other day was called to the cause, is an enormous match.
de soldados como Pala, Germán, que el otro día fue llamado a la causa, es un partido enorme.
但我们知道，他将永远在那里。
But we know that, that he will always be there.
Pero eso sabemos, que él siempre va a estar.
所以就不一一列举了，还有很多我们不认识的选手……
So not to name one by one, there are a lot of players that we don't know...
Entonces para no nombrar uno por uno hay un montón de jugadores que no sabemos que...
虽然他们没有出现在最初11的照片中，但他们......
that although they do not appear in the photo of the initial 11, they are...
que aunque no salen en la foto del 11 inicial, son...
我会告诉你，它们和那些一样重要......
I would tell you that they are just as important as those...
te diría que igual de importantes que los que...
那些一开始就出去玩的人，因为他们是保持团队良好状态的人，最重要的是，当轮到他们玩时，他们表现出色。
that those who go out to play at the beginning because they are the ones who keep the group well and, above all, when it is their turn to play, they perform.
que los que salen a jugar de inicio porque son los que mantienen al grupo bien y sobre todo cuando les toca jugar, rinden.
你好，莱昂内尔。
Hello, Leonel.
Hola, Leonel.
埃斯特万·戈多伊（Esteban Godoy），来自《足球纪事》（Crónica Edictos de Fútbol）。
Esteban Godoy from Crónica Edictos de Fútbol.
Esteban Godoy de Crónica Edictos de Fútbol.
显然，您所在的团队竞争非常激烈。
Obviously you are in a hypercompetitive team.
Obviamente estás en una selección hipercompetitiva.
他赢得了一切，世界冠军，美国双料冠军。
He has won everything, world champion, double champion of America.
Ha ganado de todo, campeón del mundo, doble bicampeón de América.
也许这场比赛最好的版本并不是在美洲杯上看到的。
Perhaps the best version of the game was not seen in the Copa América.
Tal vez en la Copa América no se vio la mejor versión de juego.
你觉得此时此刻阿根廷在你的周期中表现得更好吗？
Do you feel that at this moment Argentina is playing better in your cycle?
¿Vos sentís que en este momento Argentina está jugando mejor en tu ciclo?
比以往任何时候都更好，或者你以前有更好的表现吗？
Better than ever or did you have better performances before?
¿Mejor que nunca o tuvo anteriormente mejores actuaciones?
你知道会发生什么吗？
Do you know what happens?
¿Sabes lo que pasa?
玩得很好，从我的角度来看，有很多组件，很多组件
play well there are a lot of components from my point of view a lot of components that
jugar bien hay un montón de componentes de mi punto de vista un montón de componentes que
这不仅仅是打得好、传球 20 次以及……
It's not just about playing well, passing the ball 20 times and...
No solo es jugar bien, pasarse la pelota 20 veces y...
不仅射门，有时你还必须理解比赛，我相信这支球队
shoot at goal, not only, there are times when you have to understand the game and I believe that this team
tirar al arco, no solo, hay veces que hay que entender el partido y yo creo que esta selección lo que
进步的是对每场比赛的理解。
What has improved is understanding each game.
Lo que ha mejorado es entender cada partido.
今天不是一场轻松的比赛，然后变得轻松，但球场速度很快，他们有
Today was not an easy game, then it became easy but the court was fast, they had
hoy no era un partido fácil después se hizo fácil pero la cancha estaba rápida ellos tenían
球后面的十一名球员，你必须非常精确才能到达
to the eleven players behind the ball and you had to be very precise to reach
a los once jugadores detrás de la pelota y había que ser muy preciso para llegar a
一个进球，幸运的是，比赛开始了，然后又是另一场比赛，但我确实认为
a goal and well luckily the game opened and then it was another game but I do think that
a gol y bueno por suerte el partido se abrió y ya después fue otro partido pero sí creo que
至于比赛，随着时间的推移，他会更好地理解每场比赛该做什么。
As for the game, he understands much better what to do in each game, as time gives you that.
que en cuanto a juego entiende mucho mejor lo que hay que hacer cada partido, que eso te lo va dando el tiempo.
我们打得比这场更好 我确信我们打了一场比这场更好的比赛 当我们获胜时
match we have played better than this one I am sure we have played a better match than this one it happens that when we win
partido hemos jugado a lo mejor mejor que éste seguro seguro que hemos jugado partido mejor que éste pasa que cuando ganamos
有了狮子座的目标，一切就都看得见了。
With Leo's goals, everything is seen.
con los goles de Leo, todo se ve.
它被放大了，但我们肯定比现在踢得更好
It is magnified but we have played better than now for sure
se magnifica pero hemos jugado mejor que ahora seguro
但我们确实更了解如何玩，而时间可以让你了解这一点。
But we do understand much better how to play and time gives you that.
pero sí que entendemos mucho mejor cómo hay que jugar y eso te lo va dando el tiempo.
你好，莱昂内尔。
Hello, Lionel.
Hola, Lionel.
阿德里安·德·本尼迪克蒂第 12 页。
Adrián de Benedicti para Página 12.
在周四委内瑞拉发生的事情以及今天的结果之后。
after what happened on Thursday in Venezuela and beyond today's result.
después de lo que pasó el jueves en Venezuela y más allá del resultado de hoy.
今天您想改进游戏的某个特定方面吗？
Was there a specific aspect of the game that you wanted to improve today?
¿Había un aspecto puntual del juego que vos querías que hoy se mejorara?
嗯，我们的比赛和委内瑞拉的比赛不同。
Well, we played differently than the Venezuela game.
Bueno, jugamos diferente al partido de Venezuela.
我们如何准备委内瑞拉的比赛 我们在委内瑞拉的比赛方式有所不同 我们与蒂亚戈一起准备了比赛
how we prepared the venezuelan game we played differently in venezuela we had prepared with tiago wide open and
como preparamos el partido venezolano jugamos diferente en venezuela habíamos preparado con tiago bien abierto y
洛塞尔索在右边，我们准备了另一场比赛。
and Lo Celso was on the right, we had prepared another game.
y estaba Lo Celso a la derecha, habíamos preparado otro partido.
今天我们准备了一份不同的。
Today we prepare a different one.
Hoy preparamos otro diferente.
好吧，这就是我说每个游戏都是一个故事的地方，我不会说除了保留游戏精神之外的故事。
And well, that's where I say that each game is a story, I don't say a story beyond preserving the spirit of the game.
y bueno es ahí donde digo que cada partido es una no digo una historia más allá de conservar el espíritu del
比赛和恢复快球的方式和准备工作并不完全相同。
of play and recovering the fast ball, the games and preparations are not all the same.
de juego y de recuperar la pelota rápida, los partidos y las preparaciones no son todas iguales.
但是是的，尝试过什么
but yes what was tried
pero sí lo que se intentó
为了准备，朱莉安娜来到了终点，它不是 11，也不是 9，位置有点偏。
to prepare, juliana came to an end and it was not an 11 but not a 9 either in a position that was a bit
prepararse llegó a cabo lo de juliana y no siendo un 11 pero tampoco un 9 en una posición un poco
妨碍对手得分。
that it bothers the opponent to score.
que al rival le molesta marcar.
塔利菲科进攻或不进攻取决于比赛的进展，因为他也无法摆脱太多，因为他们的反击能力很强。
and with Taliafico attacking or not attacking depending on how the play was going because he couldn't get away with much either because they were good on the counter.
y con Taliafico atacando o no atacando según cómo esté la jugada porque tampoco podía desprenderse mucho porque ellos eran buenos a la contra.
他去的时候是因为他的攀爬非常安全。
When he went it was because his climb was very safe.
Cuando fue fue porque era muy segura la subida de él.
嗯，团队做对了。
Well, the team got it right.
Bueno, el equipo lo entendió bien.
是的，确实，我们很满意。
And yes, truly, we are satisfied.
Y eso sí, en verdad, estamos satisfechos.
克服了当天出现的所有困难，才成就了今晚的精彩表演。
with all the difficulties that arose on this date to this superb performance tonight.
con todas las dificultades que se presentaron en esta fecha a esta soberbia actuación de esta noche.
教练是否享受短短几天的成功？
Does the coach enjoy this success in just a few days?
¿El técnico disfruta de este éxito en pocas jornadas?
距离接下来的预选赛还有一个月的时间。
with one month left to face the next qualifying matches.
a falta de un mes para enfrentar los próximos partidos de eliminatoria.
你无法享受它，几个小时后你开始思考巴拉圭和秘鲁。
You can't enjoy it and in a few hours you start thinking about Paraguay and Peru.
no se puede disfrutar y ya en pocas horas se empiezan a pensar en Paraguay y en Perú.
球员们去热身的时候，我们看了一会儿比赛……
During the time that the players went to warm up, we were watching the game for a while...
En el tiempo que los jugadores se fueron a hacer el calentamiento, nosotros estábamos viendo un rato el partido de...
从巴拉圭我们已经看到了，所以最终这是我们的工作，我们喜欢它
From Paraguay we are already seeing and it is so in the end it is our job we like it
de paraguay ya estamos viendo y es así es que al final es nuestro trabajo nos gusta
享受的时间很短，很少，但是……
and the time of enjoyment is short, it is little, but...
y el tiempo de disfrute es corto, es poco, pero...
我认为当我们在现场、当我们在一起、当我们和教练组在一起时，我们会感到最大的享受。
I think we have the greatest enjoyment when we are on the premises, when we are all together, when we are with the coaching staff.
Creo que el disfrute grande lo tenemos cuando estamos en el predio, cuando estamos todos juntos, cuando estamos con el cuerpo técnico.
准备训练，和一些伙伴在一起，这些都是一个人享受的时刻。
Preparing for training, having some mates, those are the moments that one enjoys.
preparando el entrenamiento, tomando unos mates, esos son los momentos que uno disfruta.
其中，嗯，我们……
and of which, well, and we are...
y de lo cual, bueno, y estamos...
我们没事。
We're ok.
Estamos bien.
今天是平静一点的一天，但从明天开始……
Today is a day to be a little calmer, but starting tomorrow...
Hoy es un día para estar un poquito más tranquilos, pero a partir de mañana ya...
想想接下来会发生什么，因为他们是两个重要的竞争对手，我们已经知道季后赛是什么。
Think about what's coming because they are two serious rivals and we already know what these playoffs are.
pensar en lo que viene porque son dos rivales de cuidado y ya sabemos lo que son estas eliminatorias.
这里是莱昂内尔 (Lionel)、卢卡斯·加蒂 (Lucas Gatti) 代表 Ciudadano。
Here Lionel, Lucas Gatti for Ciudadano.
Acá Lionel, Lucas Gatti para Ciudadano.
首先我问你关于切尔西的事，谁被排除在外了……
First I ask you about Chelsea, who was left out...
Primero te pregunto por lo Chelsea, que quedó fuera...
从替补席上，然后我问你
from the Substitutes Bench and then I ask you
del Banco de Suplentes y después te pregunto
这支球队有什么优势，一胜二负、三球之差？
What does this team have that winning one, two to zero, a difference of three goals?
¿Qué tiene este equipo que ganando uno, dos a cero, diferencia de tres goles?
继续寻找越来越多的东西。
keep searching more and more.
sigue buscando más y más.
这支永不放弃的团队到底有何想法？
What is the idea of ​​this team that never gave up?
¿Cuál es la idea de este equipo que no bajó los brazos en ningún momento?
嗯，切尔西昨天在训练中......
Well, Chelsea yesterday at training...
Bueno, los Chelsea ayer en el entrenamiento...
他感觉不舒服，所以他没有参加
He didn't feel well and that's why he wasn't part of
no se sentió bien y por eso no formó parte de
团队有问题
of the team had a problem
del equipo tuvo un problema
它被称为肌肉发达，我不知道它的程度，因为它非常......
It's called muscular and I don't know the extent of it because it was all very...
se llama muscular y no sé el alcance porque fue todo muy...
在最后一次训练中，我们不想冒险，因为它非常接近。
in the last training session and we preferred not to risk it because it was very close.
en el último entrenamiento y preferimos no arriesgarlo porque era muy cercano.
无论你喜欢与否，有时考虑球员、考虑他的俱乐部是很重要的。
Whether you like it or not, sometimes it is important to think about the player, about his club.
Quieras o no a veces es importante pensar en el jugador, en su club.
不要冒险。
and not risk it.
y no arriesgarlo.
我们剥夺了他们的足球机会，但是哦，好吧。
We deprive ourselves of their football, but oh well.
Nos privamos de su fútbol, pero bueno.
这就是他的遭遇。
That's what happened to him.
Eso fue lo que pasó con él.
我认为这支球队拥有的就是打球的欲望。
And I think what this team has is the desire to play ball.
Y yo creo que lo que tiene este equipo es ganas de jugar a la pelota.
聚在一起 聚在一起玩得很开心 他们不会这样对你
get together get together have a good time they don't do it to you
juntarse juntarse pasársela que no te no te hagan
伤害就像你在家里玩的时候你想要攻击然后......
damage like when you were playing at home that you wanted to attack and then...
daño como cuando jugabas en tu casa que vos querías atacar y después...
不要让他们对你得分。
Don't let them score against you.
que no te hagan gol.
或多或少是相似的。
It's more or less similar.
Es más o menos parecido.
他们感觉很舒服，他们很舒服推卸责任，试图
and they feel comfortable, they feel comfortable passing the buck, trying to
y ellos se sienten cómodos, se sienten cómodos pasándose la pelota, intentando
快速而良好地恢复它，有时可以，有时则不能。
recover it quickly and well, there are times you can and there are times you can't.
recuperarla rápido y bueno hay veces que se puede y hay veces que no.
重要的是团队总是在努力。
The important thing is that the team always tries.
Lo importante es que el equipo siempre lo intenta.
晚上好，莱昂内尔。
Good evening, Lionel.
Buenas noches, Lionel.
首先，祝贺您取得胜利。
First of all, congratulations on the victory.
Primero que nada, felicidades por la victoria.
通过 FM Meraki AM690，问您两个问题，一个问题。
by FM Meraki AM690, ask you two questions, one individual.
por FM Meraki AM690, hacerte dos consultas, una individual.
对于蒂亚戈·阿尔马达来说，他在第一场比赛中就取得了冠军，今天他进场并且打进了一个进球，你在他身上看到了什么，让他参加这两场比赛？
for Tiago Almada who played the title of the first game, today he entered and it is a goal, what did you see in him to put him in these two games?
por Tiago Almada que jugó el título del primer partido, hoy ingresó y es un gol, ¿qué viste en él para ponerlo en estos dos partidos?
而且如果你感受到阿根廷队比赛时的压力，国家队......
and also if you feel the pressure that when Argentina plays, the national team...
y también si sentís la presión de que cuando juega la Argentina, la selección...
如果他们感受到压力的话，他们会让国家幸福，他们会团结国家。
They make the country happy, they unite the country, if they feel that pressure.
hacen feliz al país, unen al país, si sienten esa presión.
第二个比较容易，我们反而感到压力。
The second is easier, we feel pressure on the contrary.
La segunda es más fácil, nos sentimos presión al contrario.
如果人们感到快乐，我希望那是压力。
If people are happy, I wish that were pressure.
Si la gente es feliz, ojalá fuera presión eso.
还有其他一些更...
There are other things that are more...
Hay otras cosas que son más...
但对我们来说，令人难以置信的是，人们喜欢它，而且当选择在那里时......
but for us it is incredible that people enjoy it and that when the selection is there...
pero para nosotros es increíble que la gente disfrute y que cuando esté la selección esté...
迷上了电视，这是……
hooked on television and it's something...
enganchada en la televisión y es algo...
很漂亮。
Very pretty.
Muy lindo.
蒂亚戈在他的球队中表现非常出色。
And well, Thiago is having a very good presence in his team.
Y bueno, Thiago está teniendo un muy buen presente en su equipo.
他在一个对我们有用的位置上踢球，踢左边路，有时也踢内线。
He is playing in a position in which he can be useful to us, playing on the left, sometimes going inside.
Está jugando en una posición en la cual a nosotros nos puede valer, jugando por izquierda, a veces metiéndose para dentro.
考虑到我们失去了来自加纳乔的尼科·冈萨雷斯，他们无法在那里踢球，蒂亚戈是其中之一。
Given the loss we had of Nico González, from Garnacho, people who couldn't play there, Thiago is one of those who
ante la baja que tuvimos de Nico González, de Garnacho, gente que no podía jugar ahí, Thiago es uno de los que nos
他可以在那里踢球，即使这不是他的自然位置，他理解在那里踢球，他理解并且理解得很好
he can play there even though it is not his natural position he understands playing there he understands and understands it well
puede jugar ahí aunque no es su posición natural entiende jugar ahí entiende y lo entiende bien
所以一把扇子打开了，我们总是说，当一个人离开间隙时，另一个人进入，现在好了
so a fan opened and what we always say when one leaves a gap another enters and well now
así que se abrió un abanico y lo que siempre decimos cuando uno deja un hueco entra otro y bueno ahora
让我们看看下一次通话中会发生什么。
Let's see what happens in the next call.
a ver qué pasa en la siguiente convocatoria.
晚上好，第 10 广播电台的莱昂内尔·布鲁诺·吉佐。
Good evening, Lionel Bruno Guizzo for Radio 10.
Buenas noches, Lionel Bruno Guizzo para Radio 10.
告诉你效率对于教练组和球队今天的进球有多么重要。
tell you how important effectiveness is for the coaching staff and scoring goals like the team did today.
contarte qué tan importante es para el cuerpo técnico la efectividad y golear como lo hizo hoy el equipo.
太感谢了。
Thank you so much.
Muchas gracias.
这很重要，尤其是前锋进球。
It is important, especially that the forwards score goals.
Es importante, sobre todo que hagan goles los delanteros.
让我们快乐并且
makes us happy and
nos pone contentos y
很高兴朱利安和劳塔罗都进球了，老师决定了莱奥。
and happy that both Julián and Lautaro have scored a goal and the teacher decides Leo.
y felices que tanto Julián como Lautaro hayan hecho gol y el maestro decide Leo.
这支球队一直都有机会，已经有了目标，并且将继续凭借其锋线球员的素质来实现这一目标。
This team has always had a chance, it has had a goal and it will continue to do so with the quality of players it has up front.
Este equipo siempre ha tenido chance, ha tenido gol y lo va a seguir teniendo con esa calidad de jugadores que tiene adelante.